# **Kelly Tate**

Seattle, Washington | 206-580-3278 | kelly.tate.dev@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

# **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Recent graduate of Ada Developers Academy full stack software engineering boot camp with a passion for continuous learning, problem-solving, and optimization. Transitioning to software development after 4+ years of study in computer science and development. Bringing leadership, communication, creativity, and versatility honed through 7+ years of teaching and over 9 years of collaborating in fast-paced, customer-focused retail and marketing environments.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, Java, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP
 Frameworks & Libraries: Flask, Django, React, Node, Spring Boot, WordPress

Tools: Git, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

• **Testing:** Pytest, JUnit, Jest

• Cloud Technologies: Heroku, GCP, AWS, OpenShift

• Development Environments: VSCode, IntelliJ, PyCharm, Eclipse, Xcode

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Ada Developers Academy CMS - Website

CMS site for non-profit coding bootcamp built on WordPress with PHP and CSS

- Collaborated on migration to a new WordPress implementation to consolidate theme customization and improve site maintainability
- Incorporated Agile principles using a Kanban approach to task management, accountability, and communication, and pair-programming to ensure consistency for the 2-member developer team
- Improved SEO performance and streamlined the editing workflow for an administrative staff of 20+

# Limn - Github

Django social media journal app integrating APIs including Spotify, LocationIQ, and Cloudinary

- Collaborated on a 2-person team throughout the development lifecycle, from determining requirements, wireframes, database design, and testing to implementation and debugging with Django, Pytest, and PostgreSQL and deployment with Heroku
- Enhanced multimedia journal entries with calls to 5+ external APIs for attachment of images, videos, single tracks and playlists, location mapping, calendars, and data visualizations

#### **Inspiration Board** – Github

Message board app using API calls between React and the Flask and PostgreSQL backend

- Developed in coordination with a 5-member development team, according to provided specifications using Kanban techniques for communication and Git version control and code reviews
- Connected Flask CRUD API functionality with React frontend allowing users to create, view, and like brief
  inspirational messages using React components; tested with Pytest and Jest

#### **Event Calendar**

Event planning calendar built with a Java backend and Swing GUI

- Built according to provided CRUD specifications for organizing and managing event data within a calendar; tested with JUnit
- Designed Swing GUI for an intuitive user experience across 12+ user operations

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# **Ada Developers Academy**

Seattle, WA

Full Stack Engineer Intern

2023 - current

- Established requirements for a 4-month project to implement a clean-code rebuild of a CMS-powered website in partnership with marketing and leadership teams
- Developed layouts and reusable blocks according to marketing team specifications increasing workflow speed for non-technical staff by 30%

Whole Foods Market Chapel Hill, NC

**Grocery Team Trainer** 

2019 - 2022

- Named 2021 Regional All-Star Team Member of the Year for leadership and performance at a store of 200+
- Spearheaded workflow optimization for the grocery team's weekly performance report reducing execution time by 25%

# **Self-Employed Photographer**

Baton Rouge, LA; Kansas City, MO/KS

Real Estate Photographer

2013 - 2019

 Pioneered expansion market as an exclusive contract photographer for New Orleans-based small business, establishing loyal relationships with local agents, increasing the company's service markets by 20%

# **Louisiana State University School of Art**

Baton Rouge, LA

Instructor of Art

2009 - 2014

• Taught 5+ course topics ranging from basic to advanced applications of photography and basic design and digital art

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Ada Developers Academy**

2022 - 2023

Full Stack Web Development

Python, Flask, Django, JavaScript, React

**Computer Science Fundamentals** 

• Data structures and algorithms

## **Wake Tech Community College**

2019 - 2022

Certificates: Programming Fundamentals, C++ Programming, Java Programming

- Cloud application development: AWS, GCP, OpenShift, VMware
- Agile Development: Scrum, Kanban

## **Louisiana State University**

2008 - 2011

Master of Fine Arts – Photography

Bachelor of Arts - German Language & Literature